atosworldline.com 2018-09-06

# Worldline | Privacy

Your privacy matters to Worldline.

You are currently visiting the Worldline website.

You can decide to share Personal Data with Worldline, when subscribing to our newsletter or when registering for Worldline’ Premium Services. The Personal Data we may collect as a result of such subscription will be processed only by Worldline for the sole purpose of ensuring you are delivered with the appropriate services. None of these data will be shared with third parties.

Because data protection and security matters, the Worldline website is hosted in the European Union and Switzerland in order to guarantee an appropriate level of protection to all data that are collected and processed. Application support may be made e.g. from Worldline India. The transfers resulting from such support would be framed with the EU model clauses or Atos Binding Corporate Rules. This way we ensure that the Personal data transferred benefit from the same level of protection as if they had stayed in the EU.

  Of course, you have the right to request access, amendment, erasure or receiving an electronic copy of your Personal Data. To exercise this right, you can contact the Group Data Protection Office at [dataprotection@worldline.com](mailto:dataprotection@worldline.com).

This Privacy Notice was published on 3 July 2014 and updated on 25 May 2018. It may be amended from time to time. We invite you to consult this page regularly.

### Atos Binding Corporate Rules

Worldline is part of the Atos Group. Atos is the first IT company to have obtained approval of its [Binding Corporate Rules (BCRs)](https://atos.net/content/dam/global/documents/atos-binding-corporate-rules.pdf "BCR") by European data protection authorities both as a data controller and a processor. This approval evidences Atos’ commitment to the protection not only of its own data but also that of its clients: all Atos entities provide a very strong level of protection to personal data, regardless of their location in the world. The BCR are a commitment whereby the companies of the ATOS Group undertake to process personal data in accordance with a stringent level of protection to personal data. This applies to personal data it processes for its own needs (employee data, etc.) but also for the needs of its customers, therefore allowing the free flow of personal data between the companies of the ATOS Group.

### Cookies

Worldline takes users’ privacy very seriously and is committed to comply with the EU Directive on privacy in the electronic communications. For this purpose we have developed the following notice which intends to give you all the keys to manage the cookies we collect while you visit our website.

### What is a cookie?

Cookies are small files which are downloaded on to a device when the user accesses to certain websites. Cookies allow a website to recognize users and to understand the users’ navigation on different websites.

In practice, the website you visit sends information to the browser which then creates a text file. Every time the user goes back to the same website, the browser retrieves and sends this file to the website's server.

### Worldline Cookies  

Worldline intends to ensure that you enjoy your experience on our website. For this reason, when visiting our Worldline website, cookies are installed on your device.

When surfing on Worldline website(s), data logs of your surfing activity may be collected with the purpose of understanding aggregate usage of features and pages. For this very purpose we use Google Analytics and Eloqua.  
Google Analytics enables Worldline to view how you interact with website content. Please note that in order to avoid the collection of your Personal Data by Google, we have set up the tool in a manner which prevents the collection of IP addresses. Neither Worldline nor Google are able to identify you and your online activity. Worldline also uses 3rd party persistent cookies from Eloqua to collect information about your surfing activity.

### How long does Worldline keep the cookies?

Cookies remain on your computer for no longer than 24 months and you can decide to delete all cookies anytime when going into your browser settings.  

###   
Cookies settings  

If you don’t agree with the use of such cookies, you can set up your browser to limit or exclude their use. Your browser may provide you with information and control over cookies. You can set your browser to alert you when a cookie is being used, and accept or reject the cookie. You can also set your browser to refuse all cookies or accept only cookies returned to the originating servers. You can generally disable the cookie feature on your browser without affecting their ability to use the Worldline website(s).

To make sure you find out your way on how to change the settings, here are a few links that may be useful to configure appropriately the different browser you may be using.

### **Purpose of the cookies**

Please note that these settings are only valid for the pages created and owned by Worldline Group. When we embody link to external websites and that you click on these links you leave our website and therefore the settings and policy applying to our website no longer applies. You should consider the new website cookies policy and settings.

### **Objections**

As far as we are asking your personal data on our website you will have several opportunities to object to receiving messages from us. If you would like to have your personal data deleted from our database in order to no longer receive messages, please contact [infoWL@worldline.com](mailto:infoWL@worldline.com).
